谨以此汉化字幕献给六年来对电锯系列无比忠诚的淀粉们
发行：狮门影业
你好，海德先生，或者用在医院里的称呼叫你：泽普
游戏结束
制作
扭曲电影
制片人
伯格/寇尔斯/霍夫曼（已故）
导演
凯文・格劳特
他们怎么了？这是在干嘛？
什么情况。。。
What is this?
咋的了这是？
What the fuck?
-你在这干嘛呢？
-What are you doing here?
-你又在这干嘛呢？
-我被铐住啦！
-I'm locked
-我也是啊！
-Me too
-这算枕么一回事？！
-大件事了！
-快来人救救我们！救命！！！
-Somebody help us!Someone help us!
-喂？额。这里出事了
-Hello...I think...
-啊？迪娜？！
-Dina!
-班哥。。。
-Brad!
-小瑞。。。
-Ryan...
-亲爱的？你没事吧？
-Baby, are you okay?
-快放我下来！！救命啊！救人呐！！
-Get me outta here!Help us!Help us!
-宝贝。。
-Baby...
喂！！报警啊！！
Hey!Call the police
-快把窗户打破！！！砸吧！
-Hey!Break the glass!Break!
-大家小心玻璃！
-Get out, everyone!
使劲！
Breaking!
-救救我！！
-Get me out!
-再来！
-Break glass!
你好，班德，你好，瑞恩
Hello, Brad，Hello, Ryan
我想玩个游戏
I want to play a game
单纯被耍很天真，爬墙劈腿几度闻？
The same woman has played each of you for a fool
玩弄两男不顾情，可怜痴心挂泪痕
manipulating your love for her and causing nothing but pain
利欲熏心贪金银
Her fun and games pushed you both
诱人犯法且违伦
to break the law to fulfill her material needs
蛇蝎心肠拜月女
She is toxic. And today
群众围观斩情绳
all of your transformations will be made public
别听他哈三话四！班哥！
He's a fucking liar!Brad!
三P终需少一人
Now you will choose who will drop out of this triangle
决定生死在一分
for within sixty seconds, one of you must die
若欲怜香把玉疼
If you wish to save her，then the saws
推锯虎斗又龙争
must be pushed all the way to one side or the other
杀敌抱得美人归，海选超级小男生
sparing her while proving who is indeed the alpha male
你们这群混账看耍猴呐？！快帮帮我们！！
What the fuck are you looking at?Do something!
试问阁下有无种，果断丢弃花心人
Are you both strong enough to walk away from
what is destroying you
劝君莫再吃干醋，蛋定自如解心藤
or will you fight one more time for the heart that binds?
电光石火六十秒，不问苍生问自身
You have sixty seconds to start. Live or die. Make your choice
卧！槽！
Oh!Fuck!
放我下来！！
Get me out of here!
-你丫敢动我？！
-What are you doing?!
-先下手为强，后下手遭殃！
-Me or you,asshole!It shouldn't be me!!
-班哥！我。。我好爱你！班哥！
-Brad!I...Brad, I love you!
-啥？！
-What?
我也爱你，宝贝！
I love you,too,baby!
-快！快推！
-Do it! Do it!
-神马？！
-What?!
-快锯死他！动手啊！！
-Kill him!Brad!
-你这婊子。。。
-Stupid bitch!
杀啊！杀了他！！
Do it!Do it!
-你爱他？
-You loved him?
-不是的！
-No.
-不再爱我了是嘛？！
-You loved him more than me?!
-不是的！我是被逼的
-No..I had to say that..
小瑞，我坠爱你了！求你救救我。。
I've always loved you!Do this for me,please
杀了他！杀了班德！上吧！！
kill him!kill him! Do it!
贱人！
You're lying!
-你干熟么！！
-你是个贱女人！
这毒蛇在玩我们！操你妈！操你妈逼！
She's a liar!Fuck you!Fuck you!
班德！抬起头来！班德！
Brad, Brad look at me!
这种玩弄感情的烂逼，值得我们牺牲自己去救吗？！
不值得！班德！绝对不值得！
对不对！
Right?
对！
Yes!
-你们两个死太监要干甚么？！
-What the fuck are you doing, you fucking asshole?!
-我们要和你一刀两断！迪娜！
-I think we're breaking up with you, Dina!
不要！！不要啊！！！啊！！！
行开！差人做S！
大慈大悲观世音菩萨。。。。
片名：《电锯惊魂3D》
==百度电锯惊魂吧字幕组==
听译：唐朝娃 水浒三国金刚 洁Jazzy
校对：水浒三国金刚
提携：班班 谬谬 幻象记忆NB Woozie
压制：呼啸瑞
-游戏结束！
-不，不！！放开我！婊子！
“今晚，在一座原名‘若梵’的废弃动物园中
发生了多起性质恶劣的拼图杀人游戏命案
死者包括保护伞健康保险公司副总裁威廉・伊斯盾等人
所幸的是，据警方透露，约有七名受害者存活。。。。
这些侥幸生还的幸存者
也许可以向警方和FBI提供宝贵线索
我们来连线正在现场的本台记者托尼・盖别墅
托尼你好”
市公安局
-嘿！罗杰
-Hey,Rogers
-来了啊
-Hey,what's up
-这人谁啊？
-What've we got here?
-吉儿・塔克，“拼图狂魔”的遗孀
-That's Jill Tuck,Jigsaw's widow
-她想干嘛？
-她说她不相信FBI内帮人，也不相信重案组的伙计
-很好啊
-Oh good
-她还说
-And
-要找你
-she just wants to talk to you
-找我干神马？
-Why me?
不知道，她说只肯和你谈
I don't know,only you
看她心神不宁的样子
好吧，我去探个究竟
-加了奶精和糖
-谢谢
不客气，我是马特・吉布森，内务部高级督察
-听我的伙计说你有事找我？
-是的，但我要求拥有刑事豁免权
-你凭什么？塔克小姐
-Why do you want immunity, Ms. Tuck?
-凭我手握猛料
-Because of what I know
说来听听
Which is what?
你同意我的要求吗？
Do we have a deal?
在我这，你得先付出才会有回报，吉儿
You've got to give before you can receive in this house, Jill
我的丈夫，约翰，门下有一弟子
My husband John had an accomplice
几乎每个拼图游戏都是这个人协助约翰搞的
A person who assisted him with almost every murder
别忽悠我了，你有什么重点就直接说出来
Now, look. Don't get me wrong here
-而且必须合情合理我才肯洗耳恭听
-I'm all ears if you've got something legit
that you want put on the table
-再没人阻止他的话，他会变成一个嗜血杀人魔
-This person will go on killing until he's stopped
-你认识他，当然，他也认识你
-You know him，And he definitely knows you.
-寺伐？
-Is that right?
他就是马克・霍夫曼警官
He is Detective Mark Hoffman
-你敢发誓吗？
-敢
你愿意坦白一切包括个人隐私吗？
是的，我愿意当污点证人
Yes,I'll give you evidence, whatever you want
只要你们保证我的安全，还得给我刑事豁免权
As long as I have your protection and complete immunity
-成交吗？
-Do we have a deal?
-行，当然，我答应你
-Oh, yeah. Yeah, we have a deal
第6频道
欢迎继续收看，我们隆重欢迎正在全国巡回签名售书的
Welcome back,We're live with Bobby Dagen, whose national tour
波比・大根先生这周末带着他的力作
"Survive: My Story of Overcoming Jigsaw,"
《生存：我与电锯门不能不说的故事》光临我市
rolls into town this weekend
-您现在算是社会红人了吧？
-Now, you're quite the national phenomenon these days, aren't you?
-额。。。过奖了
-Well, thank you, Pam
谢谢，帕姆，我把那些经历写出来
It's quite flattering how many people
并不是想哗众取宠，我只是想帮助人们做点什么
have responded to my story and if I can help
我很乐意为社会出一份力
a few people along the way then I'm pleased
你从那个臭名昭著的拼图狂魔设计的杀人机关中
死里逃生，对吗？
Now, you survived a trap created by the infamous Jigsaw Killer
Correct?
-是的
-Yes, ma'am.
-我想观众朋友和我一样
-Well, everyone must ask you this question
都想知道你感受如何
what was that like?
我的人生改变了，之前从未想过会这样
Life changing. It was something I never anticipated
老实说，我真的差点被杀掉
Quite honestly, something that should've killed me
能具体点吗？说一下来龙去脉
Tell me more. Tell me about the actual experience
额。。这个这个，怎么被抓进去的我真的记不清了
I-I-I actually have no recollection of how I got there
只记得醒来时，人已经被困于死亡机关中
I just remember the feeling of waking up trapped
-我被要求将两根铁钩紧扣住我的两块胸肌
然后将自己吊向一个平台
-I had to insert two hooks into my pectoral muscles
and hoist myself up to a platform
-你自己把铁钩穿进去的？
-You put the hooks in yourself?
是的，我一度感到撑不下去了
I did. I pretty much realized I couldn't hold on much longer
以为难逃一死，可就在生死一瞬间
and I had to accept the fact that I was going to die
我忽然感觉眼前一亮，我看见了自己的一生
And then I saw something,And what I saw was my life
我的人生就像茶杯，本身就是个杯具
It was... it was a tragedy
就在那时，我的心中，我的灵魂深处
Right then. Something inside me started to grow
渐渐涌现出。。涌现出一股力量
something from the bottom of my soul and
于是我。。。于是我决定我要活下去！
我催谷起那份丧失已久的勇气
I just. I decided to live!
I found the strength I'd long thought had expired
我拉呀拉，扯啊扯
and I just yanked，and I yanked
直到爬到高台上，我把那铁钩从胸口扯出
and when I got to the top, I just ripped the hooks out of my chest
顿时。。顿时鲜血四溅，我声嘶力竭地叫喊着
It was-it was- there was blood everywhere and I just screamed
就坐在那平台上大声咆哮！我不只是逃过一劫
I just sat there and screamed Because I hadn't just survived
我凤凰涅盘！我浴火重生！
I was reborn!This was my life!
哇哦，各位观众，这就是波比・大根以及他的传奇人生
这不到点了吗？怎么没高潮后的拥吻？
This is the moment,Where's the kiss?
不知道
I don't know
好，停
跟排演的不一样
没事的，波哥。嘿美女们，请让波先生休息一下好吗？
那段感人肺腑的结尾呢？恩？
“激情演讲，感谢爱妻，牵手出场，拥抱热吻”
-我不想太招摇，知道吗？
-我知道，可那是重头戏啊！
她帮助你恢复本元，你不吻她，不感谢她
-就打动不了观众，博取不到同情心。。。
-是是是。。。
不见得吧，过于煽情就是虚伪。。。
公关的事由我处理，你管好你律师的事就行
好啦！都别说了！
-算我错了，行了吧！
-你没有错什么，波哥
你做的很好，继续保持下去
-电视采访是非常有效的宣传手段。。。
-妮娜，你歇一会儿吧
别多想了，你很棒
Don't worry about them. You looked great
-是吗？
-Yeah?
-你的事迹既真实又感人
-Your story's real and people feel that
我知道有的时候你还是会紧张不安
但我们一定要自强不息，波比
I know you can get overwhelmed at times
But we have to keep moving forward,Bobby
这是你的命运
You were meant to do this
我明白，亲爱的，我懂的
I know,I know,baby
-波哥
-什么事？
明天你要参加半个小时的拼图游戏幸存者“自救互助会”
-要同其他生还者聚一聚，很有意义的
-好的我知道了，走吧
哦上帝啊！
Oh My God!
你知道我最遗憾的一件事是什么吗？吉儿
You wanna know the only thing wrong with killing you, Jill?
就是只能杀你一次
I can only do it once
上帝啊！
Oh My God!
“埃文”
救命。。救命啊！操！！
Help me!!!Fuck!!
你好，埃文，我想玩个游戏
Hello, Evan. I want to play a game
你现在身处寰常这都是你咎由自取
The situation you find yourself in is of your own doing
你，你的女友，还有你的朋友都是种族歧视者
You, your girlfriend and your friends are all racists
操你妈！快放开我！！
You fuck you!Get me out of here!
就因为看不惯对方的肤色，你们就蛮横地欺侮他人
You have intimidated others based on their outer appearances
今天，该轮到你自己了
But today, it is you who will run scared
你的这帮狐朋狗友一向唯你是从，埃文
Your pathetic friends follow your every word, Evan
那么，如今也就只有你
Therefore, you will be the only
能解救他们和你自己了
one capable of saving them and yourself
三十秒后，支撑这辆车的千斤顶就会滑落
In thirty seconds, the jacks holding up this car will fall
这将触发一系列连锁血案
setting off a deadly chain of events
要想阻止这一切的发生
In order to stop this
你必须尽力从被万能胶粘住后背的座椅中挣脱出来
you must tear yourself away from the seat to which you are glued
然后去拉动前方的红色杠杆
and you must pull the red lever before you
当然，每一次挣扎都须付出血肉的代价
But no act comes without sacrifice
平日里，你看人只看肤色
You judged others by the color of their skin
今天你会明白：每个人内心都是同一种颜色
Today, you will learn that we are all the same color on the inside
是生是死，埃文，由你选择
Live or die, Evan. The choice is yours
救我！
Do it!
拓马的我知道！
Fuck!I know it!
-快拉呀！
-Pull,man!
-我知道！我这就拉！！
-I know!I know!
埃文！！救我啊！！！
Evan!!Get me outta here!!
操！！逼！！
快啊。。。
Do it!
你妈的快点！！
Fucking do it!
是你连累我们的！你要救我们啊！！
我整个人都酥蜜达了！
Fucking bullshit!
。。。我真希望不再做噩梦
可每次都被惊醒
周围每一处都令我回想起恐怖的经历
想起那可怕的游戏
雪梨，请继续说
Sydney，go on
说吧，你现在。。你现在很安全
Please,you're,you're in a safe place now
告诉我们你的那次经历
Tell me what happens next
阿莱克斯！不要啊！
Alex!Stop please!
雪梨，看着我
Sidney, look at me
你做出了抉择
You made a decision
-那一刻你有何感想？
-How did that make you feel?
-解脱
-Free
他老是打我
He was abusive
我。。我劝阻过他
I tried to stop it before
可是直到那时候我才下定决心
but it wasn't until that moment that I really did something
如果只能活一个，我选自己
It was him or me and I chose to live
那是我永远摆脱他的最好机会
It was the best thing that ever happened to me
说的什么屁话！
That's a bunch of bullshit!
就因为你要离开他，他就得为你去死吗？
He had to die for you to leave him?
你知道砍断手臂带给我的最大好处是什么吗？
You know the best thing that happened to me after having to cut off my own arm
那就是我现在去超市停车可以停残疾人车位了！
is handicapped parking at the damn mall!
这些人到底在拍什么玩意儿？
What the hell is a camera here for, anyway?
我在这说明一点
I am simply here to illustrate the fact that
“大难不死，必有后福”
a traumatic experience such as the kind that each one of us have been forced
这就是我们自救门的宗旨
to endure can have a positive outcome.That's all
是吗？有什么后福？
Yeah. Like what?
重获新生
A new perspective on life
好好你先听我说，我知道你还未达到
未达到我这种境界，我完全能理解
Wait! I know， I understand that you're not that place yet
I understand and I respect that
不过，请你看看周围这些难友
But you look around at all these people
在遭此磨难之前他们觉得人活着是理所当然的
taking their lives for granted
但现在大家都从坎坷中学会了珍惜
Eventually they all found something positive in their experience
大家没必要为过去的事过于自责
We shouldn't be ashamed of what we've gone through
因为我们是好人！我们是坚强的好人！
Because we're good and we are strong!
我，额。。。我给大家，看样东西
I'd like everybody to look at something
瞧这，这些，是我的伤疤
Right here. These are my scars
心灵的悲痛也许可以治愈
Because our minds will heal
但肉体的伤疤却永远烙在我们身上
but these scars will never go away
疤痕绝不是耻辱的标志！
This scar should not be a symbol of shame
而应该视为一枚象征勇气的徽章！
It should be worn as a badge of courage
大家都知道，我现在主张“重视亲友”
You know, eariler, I... spoke of valuing your loved ones
说实话，在那之前，我对亲人和朋友漠不关心
But to be perfectly honest，it was something I never did prior to my ordeal
重生之后，我遇到了，值得去爱惜的人生归宿
But since then, I have found someone who has truly become my rock
小桥，你能上来一下吗
Joyce, if you could...Please.
这位就是我太太，桥毅丝
This is my lovely wife, Joyce.
-我爱你
-I love you
-我也爱你，亲爱的
-I love you, too, baby
很给力啊！
Bravo!
经历了如此痛苦不堪的恐怖事件
To be able to sustain such a traumatic experience and
还能确立人生的新方向，并加以勉励
uh, and yet find the positive in that grisly act
真的是非凡人可比的意志力，呵呵
It's a remarkable feat indeed
实在是难得
Remarkable
甚至有些近乎变态了
If not a little perverse
我想我应该可以代表大家感谢你
I'm sure I speak for everyone here
让我们能参与你的宣传活动，祝你，DVD大卖
when I say how grateful we are to be a part of your
promotional... DVD
谢谢大家
Thank you,everyone
-我来吧，先生
-I got it,sir
-谢谢
-Thank you
-嫂子，我想跟波哥谈点事。。。
-行，那我先下去  -很快就好
你送她上车吧
-没问题
-Of course
-谢谢
-Thanks
怎么了？
What's up?
内拄拐的得瑟人是谁啊？你们认识吗？
So, what's with the creepy guy with the cane? Someone I should know about?
不，我只知道他参加互助会次数比我还多，没事不用理他
No. No, he's been at these meetings longer than I have. He's fine
-好，那回酒店休息吧
-先走了
-路上小心，波哥！
-谢了
-加油！
小桥？
Joyce?
这货怎么死的？
What happened to him?
加油站里严禁吸烟，你懂的
They always tell you not to smoke at the gas station
-这些够你研究一星期的了
-好嘞
什么事，罗杰？
What's up, man?
我在58号公路的一个废物堆积场
I'm at a junkyard on 58.
怎么了？
Why?
有人报警这出了车祸
Call came in about a car crash
车祸？那关你什么事？
Car crash. Why are you there?
没那么简单，是又一场拼图游戏
It's not just a car crash. It's a trap
死了多人？
How many bodies?
残肢断体拼一块大概四具吧
Enough pieces to make four
我过来之前，禁止任何人进入现场
-包括重案组，听懂没？
-是
我马上就到
“。。。你好，埃文，我想玩个游戏
“Hello, Evan. I want to play a game
你现在身处寰常这都是你咎由自取
The situation you find yourself in is of your own doing
你，你的女友，还有你的朋友都是种族歧视者
You, your girlfriend and your friends are all racists
就因为看不惯对方的肤色，你们就蛮横地欺侮他人。。。”
You have intimidated others based on their outer appearances”
有什么看法？
What do you think?
动机是什么？有什么意图？
Why? Why this display?
为什么要选这几个人？为什么是现在玩游戏？
Why them? Why now?
他经常这样虚张声势
We know he likes to put on a show
不，一定有什么原因
No. There's gotta be something else
把尸体打包，立即装回解剖室
请海弗纳他们搜集相关线索
比如刺青，穿孔，指甲之类的
就算是蛀牙，也要告诉我
是，长官
-吉队
-什么？
霍夫曼料到你会来调查
狗日的
“吉布森，亲眼看看吧”
瞧这
快把鉴证科的叫过来
-让他们查下指纹
-好
救命！！
“生存”
你好，波比
Hello, Bobby
我想玩个游戏
I want to play a game
凭着一张能把尖人忽悠嗫了的大嘴
You have amassed wealth, fame and notoriety
你发大财，做名人，红遍大江南北
based on your story of survival
越来越多的人投奔你而来，但却几乎没人知道真相
Many have aided in your cause. Few know the truth
你是个大骗子
You are a liar
你我都清楚你根本就没玩过游戏
You and I both know you have never been in a trap
从未接受过考验
nor have you ever been tested
今天，谎言成了真实
Today, these lies will come full circle
你会认识到自己是否有资格
and you will learn if you truly have what it takes to
自称“游戏幸存者”
call yourself a survivor
这只关押你的铁笼
The cage you find yourself in
象征着你的重生
will symbolize your rebirth
小桥？！不！
Joyce?!No!
小桥！！不！！求你不要！
Joyce! No! Please, no!
接下来的一小时内，你必须接受重重考验
Within the next sixty minutes，you must
stay on the path of learning
克服种种困难，才能见到同样被囚禁起来的妻子
and traverse a series of obstacles to
obtain access to your wife who you have also deceived
如果你未能及时到达那里，她就会死去
If you fail to reach her before the clock runs out, she will die
是生是死，波比，决定权在于你
Live or die, Bobby. Make your choice
“重启人生”
波比！！救我！！
Bobby!!Help me!!
救我啊！！波比！！救命！！
Help me!! Bobby!! Help!!
放我出去！！
Let me out!!
波比？波比！
Bobby?Bobby!
什么一回事？！这到底枕么了？！
What's going on?!What's going on?!
琼等幸存者将告诉大家她们的生死经历和内心变化
那突如其来的可怕游戏
由一盘录音带开始
那一刻，那个东西
清空了我过去的一切
甚至包括痛苦
我发觉自己如同获取了新生一般
虽然肉体被游戏折磨，但在精神上感受到了光明
那神圣的阳光照耀着我，久而久之
我越发感到巴意盎然
我。。。变得更加坚强
我为此对拼图狂魔心存感激
为这场游戏发生在我身上而感激
我真心希望大家都能接受这种洗礼
真希望有人也能改变我现在的处境
但是没有人会帮我
是吗？也许你也该上电视说你被那变态整过
让你的名字也洋气洋气
“自我反省”
这玩意设计得真精妙
Well, that's a real clever design
是你的杰作还是你丈夫的？
Yours or your husbands?
一切都是他搞的
Everything was him
这就奇了怪了
Right. Well, here's my problem
为什么那上面却布满了你的指纹！
That was left for me and your fingerprints were all over it!
你说霍夫曼想杀你
When you told me Hoffman had it in for you
可你为什么不坦白他追杀你是因为你差点杀了他？
you didn't mention that it was because you tried to kill him!
现在外头又有新拼图案了，你感到意外吗？
-不
-不意外？
这么淡定？你心理变态了你知道不？
那天一看你那熊样我就知道你神经不正常了，疯婆子
好吧，疯婆子，我看这么办
在我抓到霍夫曼之前，你就呆在这吧
祝你吃住愉快
你凭什么知道他找不到我？
吉儿！这里是安全藏身处！
安全的专门用来藏身的处所，听明白没？
吉队，这有一张寄给吉儿的光盘
-霍夫曼知道这儿的地址
-西巴！有没有搞错？！
喂？
现场有一辆车轻微冒烟
拆弹组的人呢？
-罗杰？罗杰你没事吧？
-没事
你们都别动，让拆弹组的人上
他们未清理完毕之前，任何人不得靠近
收到
放吧
你好啊，吉布森
Hello, Gibson
好久不见，废话不多说
Been a long time，What I want is simple
交出吉儿・塔克
Give me Jill Tuck
她也是罪孽深重的电锯门徒，你用不着护着她
You're protecting her despite the fact that she had direct
knowledge throughout which makes her complicit in every death
我们做笔交易
I'll make you a deal
把她交给我，我就停止游戏，再也不用死人
Give her to me, the game stops,no one else dies
否则我就大开杀戒，这都是你自寻箱子
If not, everyone dies and you'll be to blame
作出抉择吧
Make your choice
时间无多
The clock's ticking
把她押到警局拘留室
四周上锁，没有我的批准
-谁也不准进！
-明白
“重新定位”
上帝啊！
救我！
波哥！！救我啊！！
帮我解开！
我动不了！
求你救救我！
好的，别着急！
“播放我”
救我！快想想法子！
你好，波比，面前这位是你的得力助手之一
Hello, Bobby. Before you is one of your trusted colleagues
多年来不断为你作宣传打广告
She has been your publicist for years
明知你是个骗子，仍不遗余力将你打造成大明星
knowing your lies, but choosing to speak no evil
靠不停地讲大话骗取暴利
She has been richly awarded for her words
而今天她只有不出声才能获得自由
but today, she will be awarded for her silence
X光照片中的钥匙
In the X-ray you will see a key
正是用来关闭机关拯救她生命的
the key to Nina's survival，which will shut off her device
你的游戏任务是：必须在一分钟内用鱼钩将胃中钥匙钓出来
But there's a catch: You have one minute to
pull the fish-hook from her stomach and unlock the device
否则，四根钻刺将让她永远保持沉默
or else the four spikes will penetrate her throat, silencing Nina forever
要注意的是，这房间内的音量
Remember, the spikes will also advance each time
每提高一分贝，钻刺就会往前伸一段
the decibel level in this room rises above a whisper
直至刺穿她的喉咙
killing her even sooner
妮娜是生是死，波比由你决定
Will Nina live or die, Bobby? Make your choice
别喊！
我们齐心协力，好吗？
来吧
安静！安静！妈的不要吵！！
我会帮你拉出来的
别！别吵吵！
拉吧！波哥！
不！！
你就不能安静一小会儿吗？！
闭上你那张鸟嘴会死啊！！
不！！佛祖啊！！不！！
《生存：我和电锯门不能不说的故事》
唔该，小姐你好，敢问芳名？
莎拉，草字头沙漠的沙
我想告诉您，我灰常欣赏您写的书
文章很能引起共鸣，读后受益匪浅
（金刚注：这位演员）
您改变了我的人生观
（是本片导演凯文・格劳特的妻子）
过奖了，谢谢你啊，肾是欣慰
万分荣幸
先生尊姓大名？
约翰，翰林院的“翰”，你要写成吉思汗的“汗”也可以
John. With an "H," without an "H." Doesn't matter
那还是写翰林院的“翰”吧
Well, John with an "H" this time
你这排场够大的啊
You got quite an army working for you here, don't you?
费了你不少口舌吧
Must be spreading a pretty good word
我们只是想邀请尽可能多的读者来参与其中
Well, we try to reach as many people as possible. You know?
你没觉得有什么不对劲的吗？
You don't see anything wrong with that?
呵呵，没有，先生，我没觉得
No. Uh, no sir. I don't
你知道吗，本人对历史情有独钟
You know, history is a passion for me
在古埃及，人们宣誓时必须这么说
In ancient Egypt, if you were speaking under oath, you were required to say
“若有半句不真，自当开矿采石！”
"If I'm lying, take me to the quarries."
你明白是什么意思吗
That mean anything to you?
不，先生，我不明白
No, sir. No, sir. It doesn't
那就听好了：如果你欺世盗名
Well, I'll tell you what it means. It means,
if you knowingly lied on the public record
那就等着接受人民的审判吧。。。
that you were subject to a period of enslavement
我说你啥意思啊？
What are you implying here, sir?
我说的够清楚了
I'm not implying anything
这位老同志，你已经得到波先生的签名了，请靠边
Move along, buddy. He signed your book
谢谢你的签名
Thanks for the signature
包装精致，但华而不实，山水有相逢，哼哼
Nice picture, but I don't need it. We've met
海大夫，吉布森要求尽快得到尸检报告
是从垃圾场那运过来的
“由你选择”
“时间无多”
看见这个没？
-是什么？
-貌似在哪见过
嘿，有发现
也许能知道下一个游戏受害者是谁
这是一家停车场的安保监控录像
此人名叫波比・大根，你认识他吗？
不认识
他是个拼图游戏幸存者
通过讲述逃生经历四处走穴赚了一大票
他妻子以及三名助手也都失踪了
“低调做人,高调做事”
小桥？
是谁？
苏三妮
波哥！！太好了！波哥！
快救救我！救我出去！
-求求你！波哥。。。
-你知道凯子在哪吗？
撒拧晓得！快救我册七啊！！快解开！
你好，波比
Hello, Bobby
现在遍布你全身的是无限恐怖
The feeling running through your body is fear
你害怕是因为还吃不准自己是否拥有生存的资质
the fear of not knowing if you have what it takes to survive
在你面前的是你的律师
Before you is your lawyer
为求私利，她无视了曾经宣誓过的《律师道德守则》
who swore the Code of Ethics, but chose to see no evil in order to benefit herself
一旦机关开始转动
Once her device begins to rotate
30秒之内，她的双眼和嘴就会被捅穿
it will pierce her eyes and mouth if you don't delay its movement for at least thirty seconds
该游戏的唯一解法是你必须走进对面那台机器
To do this, you must step into the other machine
把铁架抬至最高位，才能切断电路，减缓钻孔
and lift the bars to the highest position long enough to close the circuit
slowing down her device
如果你无所作为，那她就只好慢慢等死了
If you do nothing, she will wind to her death before the clock runs out
能不能救到她呢？做出你的决定吧
Do you have what it takes to help her? Make your choice
波比！求你了！放开我！
上帝啊！不要啊！！
救命！！求求你！！！
快啊！快啊！！
快！波比！！加油！！！
不！！！救命啊！！
救命！！
波比！！不！！！
不！！！不！！！！
你认识这人吗？
Do you know this guy?
电视上见过，但我和他不认识的
I've seen him on TV but I don't know him
那你丈夫呢？
Did your husband?
我不知道
I don't know
你确定不认识？
是，我确定
好吧
上锁
霍夫曼发来一封邮件，有个MPEG附件
-我们正在追踪他的邮箱IP地址
-查得出来吗？
这IP党很猖狂，用代理不留芳
要不要打开附件看有没有线索
打开
你好，吉布森
Hello, Gibson
我们再一次走到风口浪尖，你不交人我不怪你
Once again, we're at a moral crossroad
I don't blame you for not giving me Jill Tuck
但你的判断力不该受旧怨左右
but you shouldn't let an old grudge cloud your judgement
看看你现在的处境吧
Look to where you're being led
站在十字路口仰望，黎明天空一片晴朗
Look beyond the crossroad to the Clear Dawn
你看到了吗？
Do you see it?
成步堂。。。走！
I got it...Go!
“无视喷子”
小桥？
Joyce?
-凯子？
-Carl?
-波哥？波哥！
-Bobby?Bobby!
凯子，别急，我就在你对面
-你别动！
-你在哪？救我！
-你知道小桥在哪吗？
-我不知道啊！
我啥都看不见！我眼睛被蒙住了！！
-凯子！别乱动！
-救我啊！救救我！
不要动！
你现在半空中，离地面很高，所以千万别动！听没？
你要救我啊！波哥！！救我！！
“播放我”
-凯子，有盘录音带！
-录音带？录音带有什么用！
收声啊！我要听了！
你好，波比
站在你正对面的是你的死党凯尔
Across from you is your closest friend
他明知你在骗人，却仍然对你言听计从
He knows all your sins, yet he acts as though he hears no evil
今天，他将听到生与死的区别
Today, what he hears will be the difference between life and death
波比，你必须引导凯尔走过独木桥
Bobby, you must help Cale to walk over the planks
帮他尽快走到离你最近的位置
and get as close to you as possible
而你的任务则是穿过横梁取得那把钥匙
Find your own way across the beams to the key
就在你们中间的那个墩距上
You must get it over the last span between you
如果一分钟后你还未替他解开
If the noose around Cale's neck is not removed within sixty seconds
绞盘就会将他凌空吊死，如此一来这世上就再没人知道你的秘密
a winch will be engaged and your secret will be left hanging
凯尔是生是死，波比由你选择
Does Cale live or die, Bobby? The choice is yours
波比！
凯子！听我说！凯子！
别瞎嚷嚷了！听我讲！！
别叫了！我会过去救你的！
混蛋！还不快救我！
我马上来！
我听你的，快教我怎么走！
我要你走右边！
走右边，没事的！撸过去！
有块木板，有没有？
对对对！朝木板走去！
好了，前面还有块木板！
-然后往右边两点钟方向！
-好的！好的！
-快点！继续带路啊！
-好！继续！凭你的感觉！
-这什么玩意儿？
-是一个十字路！别管它往前走！！
别怕！
你会没事的！
前面还有根独木桥！
-用脚去感觉！
-我踩到了！
救我啊！波哥！
踏上去！别紧张！没事的！
凯子！坚持住！
我拿到钥匙了！不要吵！我这就扔给你！
两手手心朝上！在胸前摊好！准备接钥匙！
-我数三下丢过去，听没？
-好的！
一
二
三！
我擦。。。
不要啊！！
不！！！
凯尔！！！不。。。
餐具啊。。。
-啥都没
-有的，就在这
-为什么引我们来这？
-要让我想起往事
他曾在这里救过我的命
我那个时候还是个片警，有天我来这巡逻
当时这一带游荡着很多脑残犀利哥
警察！不许动！
放下枪！举起手来！
那家伙死得有点冤
他确实袭警了，但罪不至死啊
下一次，要学会秒杀
霍夫曼如此暴力执法，我不得不举报他
你欠我的
后来呢？
后来他反而升职了我却被外派了，一年后我被调回到内务部
我成功起诉了他和他三名手下
他引我们来这儿，是要报复
这地儿原来叫“十字路口生产工厂”
所以录像里说“站在十字路口”
-下一句“黎明天空晴朗”
-是什么意思？
他杀的那个人，曾住在“黎明精神病院”
是一家政府机关病院，之后没过多久就废弃了
游戏地点就在那！
我带队过去，你回警局保护吉儿！不得有误！
“珍惜亲人”
波比！！！
-小桥！！
-波比！波比！
波比！我在这儿！
小桥！我听到了！
我看得见你！听到你的声音了！
波比！我也看到你了！
-救我啊！我在这！
-知道了！老婆！我这来救你！
是谁害我们！！
-我不知道，我先想办法救你！坚持住好吗？
-波比！
这。。这。。这儿应该有盘录音带熟么的
你好，波比
Hello,Bobby
面前这扇门直通你的爱妻
Before you is the door that leads to your wife
开门之前，你得先做出一个选择
However, you must first make a choice
你可能已经猜到了，这款游戏名字就叫“厚颜无齿”
As you may have guessed, your decision
will be as difficult as pulling teeth
那扇门锁要用四个数字组合成密码打开
The lock before you requires a four-digit combination to open
想要找到这四个数字
However, if it is access you seek
就得做出真正的牺牲
then a true sacrifice will have to be made
注意看，波比
Watch and learn, Bobby
关键数字已经被刻在你其中2颗牙齿上
The necessary numbers have been etched
onto two of your teeth
那张图供你参考选择拔哪一颗牙齿
Look to the chart as a reference
for which teeth to pull
以及数字密码的排列顺序
and in which order to enter the digits
事不宜迟
Time is ticking down
早做决定
You must make your decision quickly
波比！
-这货不能让你看，亲爱的
-我的天哪
不要！
-左翼安全！-右翼安全！
-此区安全！此区安全！
游戏还在继续
-安全！
A队上！
-攻入！
-清空！突破包围！
保持戒备！
-说话
-我已人肉到那段视频的IP所在地
-在哪？
-在58号公路上的一个垃圾堆积场
-之前那个车库游戏？！
-对，没错
-弟兄们，你们继续在这搜查
-你要去哪？
-抓霍夫曼
-好，大家行动！
我是罗杰
好
怎么了？什么事？
吉队长找到了霍夫曼的老窝，游戏该收场了
又发现一个
停！
有个活的！
没法过去，我们走
你们俩，带上来福枪跟我来
“吉布森，亲眼看看吧”
把枪给我
霍夫曼！不许动！举起手来！！
“把握每天”
-老婆？
-老公！
波比我就知道你会来的！我相信你！
-我对不起你。。。
-我相信你一定能行的！
救我！救我出去！
波比！你没事吧？
肯定有其他办法
你好，波比
Hello, Bobby
几近脱胎换骨，面临最难任务
You have almost completed your rebirth
However, you will find the task will be your most difficult
娇妻带来性福，骗局最大礼物
The woman before you symbolizes your success
She is your trophy
演讲眉飞色舞，真相不肯吐露
and she has seen the good in your message
，despite its dishonest beginnings
-它说啥？什么意思啊？
--What's he talking about?Bobby?
-女方认知盲目，男方值得信服？
-Today, we will see if you can truly earn her love
吹牛不算丈夫，实战判决赢输
To prove your status as a survivor,
you must overcome the game that should be all too familiar
汝既逃生有术，何不轻松应付
You supposedly survived it once already,
so it should be easy to survive once again
铁钩穿插胸部，游戏即刻起步
Pierce the hooks through your chest muscles and the game will begin
连接延长电路，吊索解救夫妇
In order to free yourself and your wife, you must hoist yourself
with these chains and connect the extension cords above you before the clock expires
锁链用手抓住，胸肌可堪重负
Both hands will be needed to complete this task
but that should be simple,for as you claimed to understand
the pectoral muscles can easily support your weight
时光流逝飞速，珍惜世间万物
So I ask you, Bobby, will you embrace every day as if it is your last?
汝若抉择失误，妻赴黄泉之路
Will it be with your wife? Make your choice
-它什么意思？！
-很对不起，我骗了你。。。
我从没玩过什么游戏。。。
安全！
你怎可以如此道貌岸然！！
我现在就来弥补这个过错，你好好在那呆着
我是你的妻子！你连我都骗这叫我情何以堪？！
“貌似在哪见过”
“由你选择，时间无多”
“把尸体打包，立即装回解剖室”
长官，这是什么？
这是霍夫曼的监控系统，他一直在监视着我们！！
我地妈。。。
-我是帕尔玛
-听着！
马上把所有警力全部召回警局！
-什么？
-赶快！
吉队？
吉队？你还在吗？吉大队？
“警告过你”
锁住了！我们被锁住了！
毒气！快找出口！
我爱你，小桥
一直以来都很爱你
我也爱你
波比，我也爱你
吉队？
你能撑住的！你能做到的！
佛祖啊。。。
波比，我爱你
加油啊！
扯啊！波比！拉啊！
波比！你能行的！
波比！
扯啊！！
外面枕么了？
对！拉啊！
拉！
快啊！继续，就快到了！
忍住，波比！你能行的！
外面有人！
Someone's out there
上帝啊！不！！不要！！！
Oh, my god! No!
不！不要啊！不要啊！！！
Help me! Help me! Someone help me!
我找你找的要飞起啊
I've been looking for you
我现在算什么水平？
How do I look?
烂逼！
Bitch!
救命！！！
波比！加油啊！拉啊！
波比！！快点！！
赶紧的！快快！快拉！
波比！！！加把劲！！
再来！
你一定行！
波比！！
不！！！
老公！！！！
-不！！老公啊！！！
-老婆！！
-老婆！！！
-不！！
波比救我啊！！！！
小桥！！
不！！！
小桥！！小桥啊。。。。
游戏结束
在过去的数小时内，我市公安局发生了特大恶性杀人案
九位人民警察壮烈牺牲
拼图狂魔的遗孀吉儿・塔克也被暴徒杀死
案发地方圆50公里内已被警方全面封锁
市民若发现可疑人物，请立即报警
投你妈。。。。
“哥登医生 绝密”
你好，哥登医生
Hello, Dr. Gordon
你可能是我最宝贵的遗产
You are perhaps my greatest asset
恭喜你，哥登医生，你活下来了
Congratulations, Dr. Gordon，you're still alive
全靠你这几年的帮助，电锯门才得以蓬勃发展
Without you, my work over the last few years would not have been possible
这是杰夫的妻子：莲恩・戴伦医生
她是最理想的人选
瞎了我的狗眼！
“举头三尺有神灵”
最后，我要做一个非常艰难的决定
That having been said, I have a request
替我照看好吉儿
Watch over Jill
一旦她遭遇不测，就立即行动！
and should anything happen to her
I want you to act immediately on my behalf
作为回报，我会告诉你电锯门所有秘密
In return for that，I will keep no more secrets from you
我曾带你神游四方
I showed you a lot of places
但对你来说最有意义的一处，非此地莫属
but there is one that will be perhaps
the most meaningful to you
你想的太多了
I don't think so
你要干什么？！
What do you think you're doing?
你妈逼想要干什么！！
What the fuck do you think you're doing?!
喂！
Huh?!
不！！
No!!
不能这么对我！你这烂胚！！
You can't fucking do this to me!
操你妈！！不！！！
Fuck you! NO!
玩完了
Game over
不！！！！
No!!!!
《电锯惊魂3D》全片完
==百度电锯惊魂吧字幕组==
听译：唐朝娃 水浒三国金刚 洁Jazzy
校对：水浒三国金刚
提携：班班 谬谬 幻象记忆NB Woozie
压制：呼啸瑞
导演
凯文・格劳特（电锯1-5剪辑，6导演）
编剧
帕特里克・梅尔顿
马库斯・邓斯坦
（此2人为456编剧，《夜魔》导编）
制片人
格雷格・霍夫曼（05年去世）
欧伦・寇尔斯（电锯1里的问号男）
马克・伯格
执行监制
丹尼尔・杰森・海弗纳
制片
詹姆斯・温（1导演，3编剧）
雷・沃纳尔（123编剧）
托宾・贝尔         饰  “拼图狂魔”约翰・克莱默
卡斯提斯・曼迪勒   饰  “二叔”马克・霍夫曼
贝茜・拉塞尔       饰  “锯婶”吉儿・塔克
迪恩・阿姆斯特朗   饰   凯尔
查德・多内拉       饰   吉布森
吉娜・赫尔顿       饰   桥毅丝
CC查斯特・班宁顿     饰   埃文
瑞贝卡・马绍尔       饰   苏三妮
诺米・斯涅克斯       饰   妮娜
肖恩・帕特里克・弗兰内利  饰     波比・大根
加里・艾尔维斯       饰    劳伦斯・哥登医生
感谢所有淀粉陪伴SAW一路走来，电锯有你更精彩！
伟大的电锯惊魂系列万岁！伟大的中国淀粉万岁！